no yeah perfect hopefully it's a stage
like
this hopefully this will be study i'll
just briefly then you know
having you know travel so you know what
the key role of the financial
sector is where has been to basically uh
not only to mobilize uh savings effect
uh you know
you know very good effective means of
trading goods and services
but also we're looking at you know
transferring
mitigating and diversifying the risk
which you face
and some of these risks are now as i
talked about earlier you know coming
through climate
you know issues but uh the economic
impact is uh
if you just go back to the slide where a
lot of the you know the losses
insurance industry is facing you know
starting
you know mostly are related to uh
issues caused by the environment most of
you know our you know let's say water
related risks you know so
if you look at the uh the
line of losses the worldwide industry
and the insurance and insurance market
has played
has been you know going up by the year
uh india
you know you would have noticed we've
started facing a lot of floods and local
events
so you know last year this year cyclones
have gone up you know uh areas like you
know the western coast of india
you know we've started seeing cyclone
activity you know we've seen
a lot of local floods because of you
know and
you know unprecedented you know kind of
rainfall
germany had a flat event of five billion
euros which is you know came up for such
a long time
uh china's got a flood event so these
are things impact so which are coming in
various reasons for that uttarakhand
plans for example
climate related uh or you know some some
some kind of environmental issues which
you know like to these plants
and having said that our basic endeavor
has been to be able to see how we can
a you know transfer mitigate and prevent
some of these losses
but also be part of you know the nudging
process and if you could go to the next
slide
the whole attempt has been to nudge you
know and
you know and uh you just move ahead we
have to to the
next slide
so just uh you know our role you know
one is you know as someone talked about
earlier the role of capital in trying to
you know uh go towards incentivizing the
transition
uh you know financial capital you know
so even insurers are trying to exit
you know covering your coverage of risks
in you know coal-based
uh you know businesses or you know
so they're taking proactive actions to
avoid insuring some
carbon intensive oil and gas producers
people have
uh you know sort of gone out and laid uh
their
you know intentions in terms of going
forward they would stop covering it up
after a point of time
then but on the other hand incentivizing
the transition has been very very
important
uh so there are examples of
incentivizing trans
you know transportation to use much more
climate friendly fuel
uh you know in india there's been a lot
of emphasis on bringing in solar
as insurers we've been responsible in
trying to bring in covers which are very
long term covers to be able to cover uh
you know solar generation plants
uh over over the long term uh not only
in terms of
any loss which would come to them but in
terms of their you know
you know not being able to
you know give enough electricity due to
defects uh somewhere coming into the
panels
so those kind of areas we've been
working you know
a lot to be able to incentivize these
particular transitions we could move to
the next slide
so one of the key products which are you
know coming in our parametric insurances
which we tend to cover uh you know
farmers and businesses over the long
term just you know
would go back and the uh the other one
you know
is mostly looking at places uh
you know which uh products which
incentivize people to adopt uh you know
measures of improving their risk you
know businesses
mostly the manufacturing businesses
let's even down to the
human homes you know you know we are
trying to see as insurers whether we can
conduct home audits audits uh across
businesses
you know to be able to bring down their
you know
energy usage we'll stop we states you
know
be sure that we uh bring down their
productivity to their pollute and you
know hence you know
trying to make sure that you know there
are no you know covers
we've had you know big big events of
pollution like
deep water so you know so there are
possibilities of pollution here in india
so if you know trying to nudge your
businesses to be
very aware of these situations is one of
the key things
insiders have started going across the
world and you know going forward
in terms of the way forward one of the
key things
which which we as insurers would like to
do along with reinsurers is
be able to make sure that
we nudge people uh make them very very
sensitive about the fact that you can't
transfer risk indefinitely
the also trying to bring in corporate
governs
governance elements in not only the way
you use you know
you know the cost of capital but also
trying to
you know see whether capital can be used
sustainably
and that that is very very linked to
sustainability on them
you know on their business processes and
sustainability on environmental issues
so while you know the capital is coming
in a lot of
corporate governance uh uh the the role
of
investment you know the way you oversee
the investments were
you know oversee you know the return on
sustainable capital
is going to become an important part and
here in you know in charlottesville
we're looking at transferring risks so
we would make sure that some of these
risks
which we cover you know uh are us
things which we that's the businesses or
individuals to work towards
risk which we you know we ought to cover
you know
eliminate those risks between you know
our you know coming out
because of environmental issues which
you could prevent so
that's one part which we are looking at
very very strongly go to the next slide
so you you know uh there are numerous uh
you know examples of initiatives where
uh along with the
organizational event public and private
sector you know it's coming together
with the world bank and others to launch
you know climate insurance for public
good you're talking about alliances
which are talking about net zero
insurances and various forms of
protective measures which
nudge you know responsible use of uh you
know
uh capital
uh as we finally as we go forward you
know you could look at the way
next slide you know we're looking at
making sure
that there is an emphasis on
collaborating with a lot of the agencies
uh to discourage construction at
high-risk areas
and to encourage use of you know
materials which are resilient
you know so that they withstand the
effect of
you know these changes uh incentivize
policyholders to adopt practices that
arrest like climate change of course a
prediction
of uh you know we insurers live on
we run you know a lot of analytical
models or disasters so there you know we
have you know we work in collaboratively
with a lot of
other agencies who work on these you
know models to be able to understand the
impact of certain actions we take today
you know you know going for far ahead
for generations ahead
and finally and not you know well last
but not the least is that
you know we we are at the forefront
of the risk you know uh which climate
change brings to
a business and individuals and our
ability to be
you know there is a finite element of
funds available to be able to transfer
risk
so hence we need to be very very careful
to look at resting the
uh you know the risks which which are
caused due to climate changes uh you
know and so here
attack the basic elements of preventing
some of these climate changes those
risks would
you know get medicated that's the final
thought process going forward there's a
lot of work to be done going forward
with all the other agencies which are
involved
it's good to be on this panel thank you
very much again for inviting me i'm
hoping the question is going forward
okay so as i said before we proceed to
the questions at the end of all
presentations
it's okay for you